NICOLE REMY

Email: nremy@usc.edu

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicole-remy | Portfolio: https://ner-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/nicoleremy95

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Architecture, Geographic Information Science, and customer service. Self-motivated with a strong work ethic and a passion for problem solving, innovating, and learning. Experience working/communicating with stakeholders and collaborating in teams. Committed to leadership, thinking out of the box, and acquiring new skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Databases: JavaScript, Typescript, React.js, HTML, CSS, Ant Design, Material UI, Bootstrap, Materialize,

Node.js, Third Party APIs, Rest API, JSON, AJAX

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL **Applications:** Heroku, Github, Git

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate | **GPA 4.0** | **August 2020:** University of Washington, Seattle, WA 12-week remote intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Science GeoDesign | **GPA 3.61** | **May 2018:** University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA <u>Honors and Recognitions:</u> Gamma Theta Upsilon Honor Society, USC Dean Scholar Studied Geographic Information Science (GIS), big data, science, architecture, landscape architecture, urban and regional

planning, and algorithms to address challenges, issues, and opportunities presented by the built environment. Created Python queries to populate maps used for data analysis.

PROJECTS

PLANIT | https://github.com/zackdeacon/planit-backend | https://travelplanit.herokuapp.com

- MERN, mobile responsible, application allowing users to create a trip, invite guests, add suggestions, vote, chat, comment, and render a final trip itinerary
- Acted as a Project Manager updating Kandan boards, and heading communication, delegation, timelines, MVP and MDP goals. Innovated and built the voting, comment, and photo upload components
- Tools: React.js, JavaScript, node.js, Ant Design, CSS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bcrypt, express, express-sessions
- <u>Team Size</u>: 4
- Key Accomplishments: Best UX/UI (voted by professors), Best Overall Application (voted by peers)

PawsLife | https://github.com/rickyg218/PawsLife- | https://pawslife.herokuapp.com/

- Full CRUD, social networking community for pet owners seeking care and pet service providers growing business
- Front End Lead, CRUD functionality lead, created models and backend routes
- <u>Tools</u>: Handlebars, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, MySQL, MySQL2, Sequelize, Bcrypt, express, express-sessions, express-handlebars, ORM
- Team Size: 5

EXPERIENCE

Architecture Associate | BCRA Design | Seattle, WA | 2018 – 2020

Managed client relationships, timeline, budgets/savings, progress to completion/customer satisfaction. Actively engaged on 3-5 projects at a time completing over 15 projects through the design and construction phases. Created and presented proposals for clients, collaborated and engaged across multiple accounts, teams, consultants, and clients to improve processes. Designed functional, aesthetically pleasing spaces for retail, corporate office, and residential spaces optimizing user experience.

Key Accomplishments:

• 1 in 40 people in Washington State Certified in Autodesk Revit Software (at the time of certification)

• Independently designed a model/workflow for creating multi story, office building models in Revit and AutoCAD for large scale teams reducing overall production time

LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES

President: University of Southern California, Kappa Kappa Gamma: November 2016-November 2017 *Key Accomplishments:*

- Innovated a member incentive program which increased chapter attendance by 40%
- Facilitated communication and held responsibility for 250 members and an 18 person Executive Board

Sea Gal/ Professional Cheerleader: Seattle Seahawks: May 2018-July 2020

Song Girl/University Cheerleader: University of Southern California: December 2014-January 2017